TAKAHIRO ISHIKAWA

• DETAILS •

+81-90-6343-9513 sykwer@gmail.com

• LINKS •

• SKILLS •

Operating System
Virtualization
Real-time System

Workload Analysis

Linux Kernel

PROFILE

Master student majoring in computer science, especially in operating system and virtualization on embedded environments. Work experience in wide range of software engineering such as web development, applications related to machine learning, and operating system. Now working on the development and analysis of a self-driving system named Autoware.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Part-time Engineer at Tier IV, Inc., Tokyo

June 2020 — Present

Development and Analysis of self-driving systems.

Teaching Assistant at The University of Tokyo

April 2020 — September 2020

Made completely new curriculum for "System programming lab" class in Dept. of Information Science, The University of Tokyo, in which the students create self-made OS from scratch in the bare-metal environment. (<u>Github</u>)

Engineer Intern at Fixstars Corporation, Tokyo

February 2020 — February 2020

Research on unikernel running on SoC for self-driving systems.

Software Engineering Intern at Google LLC, Tokyo

September 2019 — December 2019

Window Framework team in ChromeOS ARC++. Worked on performance improvement for rendering speed in some specified Android apps.

Part-time Engineer at Preferred Networks, Inc., Tokyo

October 2018 — February 2019

Released a visualization tool named ChainerRL Visualizer as an open source project. (<u>Github</u>, <u>Article</u>)

Engineer Intern at Preferred Networks, Inc., Tokyo

August 2018 — September 2018

Research about visualization and understanding of Deep Reinforcement Learning. Designed app concepts and implemented several prototypes for the research team.

Engineer Intern at Wantedly, Inc., Tokyo

April 2017 — May 2017

Server-side and front-end development for web applications. Also engaged in middle-ware development for a Amazon SQS client service.

Web Engineer Intern at MICOLY, Inc., Tokyo

April 2016 — April 2017

Server-side and front-end development for web applications and API servers for a mobile app. Also engaged in infrastructure management.

EDUCATION

Master of Science - MS, Computer Science, The University of Tokyo

April 2020 — Present

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, System Design and Development, The University of Tokyo April 2015 — March 2020